德州市二零二零年初中学业水平考试英语试题。一听力测试，共二十五小题，一至二十小题每小题一分，二十一至二十五小题每小题两分，共计三十分。每小题约有八秒钟的答题时间。一，录音中有五个句子，每个句子听两遍，然后从每小题中选出能对每个句子做出适当反应的答语。
Let's spend this weekend in the countryside.
3. Which do you like, traditional country music or rock music?
4. You have done a good job, and we are so proud of you.
5. We can't camp at the foot of the mountain because of the rain.
二。录音中有三个句子，每个句子对应一幅图片，每个句子。听两遍，然后选择与句子内容相对应的图片。
6. You must stay away from this deep river because it's very dangerous to swim in
it. 7. The modern world is still influenced by Confucius' ideas.
8. The best way to keep healthy is to exercise more, and I think running is a good
choice. best way to keep healthy is to exercise more, and I think running is a good
choice. to keep healthy choice.
三，录音中有五组对话。听对话两遍后，从每小题中选出能回答所给问题的正确答案。
Oh, really? So tea has a history of about 5,000 years.
Question. When was tea first discovered as a drink?
It's said that Shen Nong was the first to discover tea as a drink.
really? So tea has a history of about 5,000 years.
Question. When was tea first discovered as a drink?
10. We should do something together to protect the environment.
I agree. Well, to reduce air pollution, we should ride a bike instead of driving.
Question. What is the man's advice on reducing air pollution?
We should do something together to protect the environment.
agree. Well, to reduce air pollution, we should ride a bike instead of driving.
What is the man's advice on reducing air pollution?
11. China will start building the space station Tiangong in 2020.
Wow, that's exciting news.
Then astronauts can live and do science experiments in the station.
Question. What's the name of the space station?
China will start building the space station Tiangong in 2020.
Wow, that's exciting news.
Then astronauts can live and do science experiments in the station.
Question. What's the name of the space station?
12. Look, a car hit a man on the road.
The policeman said that the driver was talking on his mobile phone.
He didn't see the man walking.
That's too dangerous.
Question. Why did the car hit the walking man?
Look, a car hit a man on the road.
The policeman said that the driver was talking on his mobile phone.
He didn't see the man walking.
That's too dangerous.
Question. Why did the car hit the walking man?
13. Excuse me, could you tell me the way to the nearest hospital?
I hurt my knee.
course. Walk along this road, turn left at the second crossing, and then you'll see
it. But I think it is a little bit far for you.
I can drive you there.
I am really thankful.
How does the woman go to the hospital?
Excuse me, could you tell me the way to the nearest hospital?
I hurt my knee.
Of course. Walk along this road, turn left at the second crossing, and then you'll
see it. But I think it is a little bit far for you.
I can drive you there.
I am really thankful.
Question. How does the woman go to the hospital?
四。录音中有一段长对话，听对话两遍后，从每小题
A, B, and Hi, Dad.
中选出能回答所给问题的正确答案。
Can we have a talk?
Sure. What's up?
Well, before I go to high school, I'm planning to do a part -time job during the
coming summer vacation.
What kind of job?
I am going to help my uncle sell computers in his company.
Sounds good. But why do you need such a job?
My classmate Jenny is going back to Canada.
I want to buy a nice present for her, so I need some money.
Nice girl. What do you want to buy?
Something special because she is my best friend.
What is it?
What about a watch?
She'll think of me when she looks at the time.
That's a good idea.
Hi, Dad. Can we have a talk?
Sure. What's up?
Well, before I go to high school, I'm planning to do a part -time job during the
coming summer vacation.
What kind of job?
I am going to help my uncle sell computers in his company.
Sounds good. But why do you need such a job?
My classmate Jenny is going back to Canada.
I want to buy a nice present for her, so I need some money.
Nice girl. What do you want to buy?
Something special because she is my best friend.
What is it?
about a watch?
She'll think of me when she looks at the time.
That's a good idea.
五。录音中有三小段独白。听独白两遍后，根据独白内容将信息配对。
18. Olivia likes traveling in her spare time.
She enjoys visiting new places, meeting different people, and having nice food.
19. grew up in an inland city, and she always wants to see the sea.
Olivia likes traveling in her spare time.
She enjoys visiting new places, meeting different people, and having nice food.
She grew up in an inland city, and she always wants to see the sea.
19. 5G technology is coming.
William is quite interested in because 5G can give him a faster online experience
and he can live a smarter life.
5G technology is coming.
William is quite interested in it because 5G can give him a faster online experience
and he can live a smarter life.
20. Australia's fires have killed over a billion animals.
Alice is an animal lover, and she feels sad about those animals'
She is trying to help and save the animals which lost their homes.
Australia's fires have killed over a billion animals.
Alice is an animal lover, and she feels sad about those animals' death.
She is trying to help and save the animals which lost their homes.
6. in the radio report to
六，听力填表。共五小题。录音播放前，你有二十秒钟。的读题时间。学校做了一个关于初中生暑假期间是否可以独自外出游玩的调查问卷，请你认真听下面一段了解调查结果和学校建议。听广播两遍后，请你根据表格。
please We have just finished the survey about could students go out alone during the
内容提示：记录相关信息，完成表格，每空一词。
summer vacation among the students, teachers, and your parents.
Here is the result.
About 56 of you students think that it's safe to go out alone because you are sure
that you can take good care of yourselves.
78 of the teachers think you'd better not go out on your own.
They think it's dangerous.
Most surprisingly, more than half of your parents agree that you are able to look
after yourselves, and they think it is a good chance to improve your abilities of
solving problems. The school's advice is you had better not go out alone.
If necessary, you should take a phone with you and keep in touch with your parents.
Remember to stay away from dangerous areas.
Dear boys and girls,
we have just finished the survey about could students go out alone during the summer
vacation. Among the students, teachers, and your parents,
here is the result.
56 of you students think that it's safe to go out alone because you are sure that
you can take good care of yourselves.
78 of the teachers think you'd better not go out on your own.
They think it's dangerous.
Most surprisingly, more than half of your parents agree that you are able to look
after yourselves, and they think it is a good chance to improve your abilities of
solving problems. The school's advice is you had better not go out alone.
If necessary, you should take a phone with you and keep in touch with your parents.
Remember to stay away from dangerous areas.
you.
听力测试到此结束，请继续做其他题目。